Daniel W. Talmadge Papers
© 2007 University of Connecticut
Daniel W. Talmadge Papers.
undated, 1949-1976.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Talmadge, Daniel W.
.5 linear feet.
The collection contains the research, publications and correspondence of Daniel W. Talmadge, a professor of Poultry Science at the University of Connecticut from 1949 until his retirement in 1979.
MSS20070012
Biography
Daniel W. Talmadge was born in Cheshire, Connecticut, and received his B.S. from the University of Maryland. He completed his graduate work at the University of Massachusetts and Pennsylvania State University. Talmadge worked as a research assistant at the University of Massachusetts (1947-1949) before his employment as an instructor at the University of Connecticut (1949). Promoted to Assistant Professor in 1951 and Associate Professor in 1967, Dr. Talmadge specialized in poultry science with a focus on incubation, embryology and hatchability studies.
Dr. Talmadge retired from the University of Connecticut on 1 October 1979.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence, publications and laboratory manuals, all concerning Talmadge's interests in various aspects of poultry science.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by topic and chronologically therein.
Series I: Papers ( undated, 1950-1976 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. See especially, the papers of Garry A. Miles.For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Chicken Chatter (1962-1967) Dodd Periodicals
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Talmadge, Daniel W.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut. Cooperative Extension Service.; University of Connecticut.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)
Subjects:
Poultry--Study and teaching--Connecticut.; Poultry Research.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Interviews.
Occupations:
Educator.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Dr. Talmadge in January 2007.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1949-1976
  - 4-H
    - Chicken-Layer Project and Broiler-Barbeque Project, undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Laying Flock Management, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Poultry Studies Series, "How to Make a still air incubator,", undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Poultry Tips, undated (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Prue Bred Poultry Project (Bantams, Artificial insemination), undated (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Surgical Capons, undated (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence
    - Committees, 1950-1976 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Intercollegiate Poultry Judging Contests, 1949-1972 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Poultry Extension, 1972-1974 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - Student Activities (Clubs, Counseling, Chick incubation and Embryology institutes), 1961-1974 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Laboratory Manuals
    - Animal Industries 54 -- Commercial egg production, undated (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - Animal Industries 209 -- Principles of poultry science, undated (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - Poultry Science 26 -- Practical poultry breeding, 1965 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Poultry Science 222 -- Introduction to avian biology, undated (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - Poultry Science 265 -- Principles of incubation and chick development, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Publications and interviews
    - "Brooding and Rearing baby chicks,", 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Radio Interviews, 1964-1971 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Scientific and applied science publications, undated, 1959-1976 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Résumé, 1978 (Box 1:, Folder 19)